Germain García Zanabria

Curriculum Vitae

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Name: Germain García Zanabria

D. of Birth: 3 July, 1991

Address: Urb. Los Incas/C-4/Cusco/Cusco/Perú

Telephone: (51) 984 145694

E-mail: germaingarcia17@gmail.com

Nationality: Peruvian
Marital Status: Single
DNI: 47589479
Passaport: 116671311



I received my Ph.D. degree [2017-2021] in Computer Science (Cs) from Sao Paulo University (USP), Brazil. I received my Master's Degree [2014-2016] in Cs at Universidad Católica San Pablo (UCSP), Peru. I conducted my Post-Doctoral research on dropout patterns in Peruvian universities at the Center for Research and Innovation in Computer Science (RICS) of UCSP. I was a visiting researcher [2019] at the Visualization Imaging and Data Analysis Center (VIDA) of New York University (NYU), USA. My areas of interest are data visualization, visual analytics, machine learning, data science, crime analysis, crime prediction, dropout analysis, geo-referenced data, Spatiotemporal analysis, and computer science for social goods.

EDUCATION

PhD. in Computer Science

2017 - 2020

University of São Paulo - Brazil

PhD. in Computer Science at the Institute of Mathematical and Computer Sciences (ICMC) of the University of São Paulo - Brazil, with focus on data science and crime data analysis.

PhD internship

2019 - 2020

New York University

VIDA- lab

Visualization Imaging and Data Analysis Center - Urban data Analysis

Master in Computer Science

2014 - 2016

Universidad Católica San Pablo

Master Degree in Computer Science, Universidad Católica San Pablo de Arequipa - Perú. research has focused on: Visualization of the information, Data visualization, Visualization of multidimensional data, multidimensional data projection.

Systems Engineering

2018 - 2012

Universidad Nacional de San Antonio Abad del Cusco

Systems Engineering Degree, Universidad Nacional de San Antonio Abad del Cusco - Perú.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Professor Oct. - 2021

Universidad Católica San Pablo

Professor in business analytics certification.

Professor

Jun. - Sep
2022

Universidad Nacional de San Antonio Abad del Cusco.

Professor Data Science and Research projects.

Professor Oct. - 2021

Universidad Católica San Pablo

Professor in Data Science certification.

Research Visitor 2019 - 2019

NEW YORK UNIVERSITY

Research project development with urban data, specifically with crime data.

Software Developer

EMP GENERACION ELECTRICA MACHUPICCHU S A

Software Developer at EGEMSA, Development server system to manage Unix backup files.

Professional Internship

2012 - 2013

EMP GENERACION ELECTRICA MACHUPICCHU S A

Supporting and Help Desk to users of enterprise systems. Software engineering and development direct to ERP systems.

Software Developer

2011 - 2012

CODE PERU

Software development directed to web applications with HTML5, JavaScript, PHP, CSS3, and C#.

RESEARCH GRANTS

CONCYTEC - FONDECYT

2014 - 2016

Concytec: Concytec: Technology and Technological Innovation – Perú, Fondecyt 011-2013 Master Program, Period: 04/2014 to 04/2016, Position: Fellowship - Multidimensional Data Visualization.

FAPESP - CEPID 2017 - 2020

CeMEAI: Center for Mathematical Sciences Applied to Industry, Fapesp #2017/05416-1, Period: 03/2017 to 12/2020, Position: Fellowship - Crime Visual Analytic.

BEPE - Fapesp CEPID

2019 - 2019

CeMEAI: Center for Mathematical Sciences Applied to Industry, Fapesp #2019/04434-1, Period: 05/2019 to 12/2019, Position: Fellowship - Urban Visual Analytic).

LINKS TO PERSONAL SITES

• Personal:

https://dina.concytec.gob.pe/appDirectorioCTI/VerDatosInvestigador.do?id_investigador=34979

• Additional CV:

http://lattes.cnpq.br/7345868777156264

• Linkedin

https://www.linkedin.com/in/germain-garcia-zanabria-165544b4/

• E-mails:

germaingarcia17@gmail.com, germain.garcia@unsaac.edu.pe, and germain.garcia@ucsp.edu.pe

PRIZES AND AWARDS

- Best Master dissertation (PEIT 2017), Universidad Católica San Pablo de Arequipa
 Perú (2017).
- Best Computer Graphics/Visualization Main Track Papers Awards, 33rd SIB-GRAPI Conference on Graphics, Patterns and Images (2020).
- Best paper Awards, (CLEI XLVII) Special Issue of CLEI (2021).
- Teacher Evaluation Highlight, Universidad Nacional San Antonio Abad del Cusco -Perú (2022).
- Upper third student, Universidad Nacional San Antonio Abad del Cusco Perú (2013).

SCIENTIFIC RESULTS

- Garcia-Zanabria, G., Silveira, J. A., Poco, J., Paiva, A., Nery, M. B., Silva, C. T., Adorno S., & Nonato, L. G. (2019). CrimAnalyzer: Understanding Crime Patterns in São Paulo. IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (2020).
- Garcia-Zanabria, G., Poco, J., Batista Nery, M., Silva, C. T., Raimundo, M., & Nonato, L. G. CriPAV: Street-Level Crime Patterns Analysis and Visualization. IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics (2021).
- Garcia-Zanabria, G., Batista Nery, M., Gomez-Nieto, E., Luis Gustavo Nonato. Mirante: A visualization tool for crime analysis in cities (2020). *Computers & Graphics*.
- Garcia-Zanabria, G., Luis Gustavo Nonato, and Erick Gomez-Nieto. iStar (i*): An interactive star coordinates approach for high-dimensional data exploration, Computers & Graphics, 60:107–118, 2016.
- Garcia-Zanabria, G., Gutierrez-Pachas, D. A., Camara-Chavez, G., Poco, J., & Gomez-Nieto, E. (2022). SDA-Vis: A Visualization System for Student Dropout Analysis Based on Counterfactual Exploration. Applied Sciences, 12(12), 5785.

- Alvarenga Silveira, J., Garcia Zanabria, G., Paiva A., Piccirillo D., Batista Nery, M., Adorno S., & Luis Gustavo Nonato(2019). São Paulo City Schools and Their Surroundings: from Non-Negative Tensor Factorization to Pattern Identification. XL Congresso Nacional de Matemática Aplicada e Computacional
- Alvarenga Silveira, J., **Garcia Zanabria**, **G.**, Paiva A., Batista Nery, M., Adorno S., & Luis Gustavo Nonato. Crime Patterns and Urban Infrastructure around São Paulo City Schools: An Analytical Study via Non-Negative Tensor Factorization (2020).
- Gutierrez-Pachas, D. A., Garcia-Zanabria, G., Cuadros-Vargas, A. J., Camara-Chavez, G., Poco, J., Gomez-Nieto, E. (2022). How Do Curricular Design Changes Impact Computer Science Programs?: A Case Study at San Pablo Catholic University in Peru. Education Sciences.
- Pachas, D. A. G., Garcia-Zanabria, G., Cuadros-Vargas, A. J., Camara-Chavez, G., Poco, J., & Gomez-Nieto, E. (2021, October). A comparative study of WHO and WHEN prediction approaches for early identification of university students at dropout risk. In 2021 XLVII Latin American Computing Conference (CLEI) (pp. 1-10). IEEE.
- Quispe-Torres, G. F., **Garcia-Zanabria**, **G.**, Vera-Olivera, H., & Enciso-Rodas, L. (2021, October). Trajectory Anomaly Detection based on Similarity Analysis. In 2021 XLVII Latin American Computing Conference (CLEI) (pp. 1-10). IEEE.
- Quispe-Torres, G. F., Garcia-Zanabria, G., Vera-Olivera, H., & Enciso-Rodas, L. (2022). Feature-based Trajectory Anomaly Detection. In 2022 CLEI electronic journal.

PERSONAL SKILLS AND COMPETENCES

Languages:

- Spanish: Understands well, speaks well, reads well, writes well.
- English: Understands well, speaks reasonably, reads well, writes well.
- Portuguese: Understands well, speaks well, reads well, writes well.
- Quechua: Understands well, speaks well, reads well

	Reading	Speaking	Writing	Undestanding
Enlglish	Advance	Reasonably	Advance	Advance
Portugues	Advance	Advance	Advance	Advance
Quechua	Reasonably	Advance	Reasonably	Advance
Spanish*	Advance	Advance	Advance	Advance